(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
#さくらみこ3D新衣装
#SakuraMiko3DNewOutfit
花月ノ夢
Kagetsu no Yume (A Moonlit Dream of Flowers)
作詞: yuiko 作曲: かんざきひろ
Lyrics: yuiko | Composition: Hiro Kanzaki
時は越え 今宵も願う
Through the ages, I make my wish again tonight
途切れぬ想い 届くようにと
Praying that my continuous feelings will reach you
定めだと 気付かないまま
Without realizing that it's fate
あなたの姿を探す
I search for your silhouette
ひとよ ひとよ
Oh, tonight... Tonight...
追いかける夢
A dream I chase
朽ち果ててしまわぬように
So it won't rot and wither away
ひらり ひらり
Fluttering... Fluttering...
舞い踊りましょう
Let us dance
赤き月に消えるまでは
Until we vanish into the red moon
口寄せて歌う
Bringing my lips close, I sing
この夢は 儚き夢
This dream is a fleeting dream
永久に続くように 願っても
Even if I wish it would last forever
伝えたい あなたにだけは
I want to tell you, and only you
物語の結末を
The end of the story
月よ 重ね
Moon, overlapping
辿り着く夢
A dream reached
闇に染まってしまわぬように
So it won't be dyed in darkness
さくら さくら
Sakura... Sakura...
咲き誇りましょう
Let us bloom in full
いつかあなたが振り向く
Until you turn around one day
その瞬間まで
Until that very moment
ひとよ ひとよ
Oh, tonight... Tonight...
語り続けよう
Let us keep telling the story
幾千の時を流れて
Flowing through thousands of years
ひらり ひらり
Fluttering... Fluttering...
ハラリ...
Fluttering down...
舞い踊る夢
A dream that dances
今宵桜の下で
Tonight, under the cherry blossoms
口寄せうさうさ
Spiritual invocation, Usa-usa
はーい！ということでみんなー！にゃっはろー！
Alright! So, everyone! Nyahharo!
にゃっはろにゃっはろにゃっはろー！うおー！
Nyahharo, nyahharo, nyahharo! Whoo!
はい！ということで、ついに！
Okay! So, finally!
さくらみこ 3D新衣装お披露目ライブ！やったー！いえーい！
It's the Sakura Miko 3D New Outfit Reveal Live! Yay!
やったやったやったやった！みんな見えてますかー？
We did it, we did it! Can everyone see me?
あ、にゃっはろー！
Ah, nyahharo!
はい！ということで、ホロライブ所属の
Okay! So, from Hololive,
エリート巫女アイドル、さくらみこでーす！
it's elite shrine maiden idol, Sakura Miko!
今日はプロレスをしません！あははは！
I won't be doing pro-wrestling today! Haha!
はい、もうアイドルに戻ったということで、
Right, since I've returned to being an idol,
いやー、どうですか？ちょっと『花月ノ夢』踊ってみたんですけど
how was it? I tried dancing to 'Hanazuki no Yume'.
いやー今日はね、ちょっとライブのコンセプトとしては、
Well, for today, as for the concept of the live show,
あのー、普段よりも、もっとエリート巫女、
um, even more than usual, it's 'Elite Miko',
っていう感じでね。まあ今日は、この後分かりますけど、
that kind of feel. You'll see later today, but
和風な曲が多めになってたりとかしております！よー！
it's going to feature a lot of Japanese-style songs!
ということで、なんとですね、あ、みんなありがとうコメント、
So, and then, ah, thanks for the comments everyone,
あ、見てますよ。あ、可愛い！みんな新衣装みこ可愛いだろー？
Yeah, I'm watching. Cute! Miko is cute in her new outfit, right?
お久しぶりの巫女服、ね？ありがとう。
Shrine maiden clothes after a while, huh? Thank you.
あの、事前にですね、さくらみこ新衣装予想を
Um, beforehand, I was asking for predictions
募集していたと思うんですけど、
for my new outfit,
やっぱりみこもね、やりたくてね。紹介！
and Miko really wanted to do this too. The showcase!
みんなもよくやってますよね、ホロライブメンバーはねよくやってるので、
Everyone else does it often, right? Hololive members do it a lot,
ちょっと今日はみこもやってみようと思いまーす！
so Miko decided to try doing it today too!
では、じゃあ早速紹介しますか！
Then, let's start the showcase right away!
じゃあちょっとね、こちらにあるので持ってきます！
Well, they're over here, so I'll go get them!
よいしょ、どっこいしょっと。いやー、いっぱい届いてたんですけど、
Heave-ho, and there we go. Man, I received so many,
一部、一部だよ！一部紹介、あ、見えてるかな？あ、はい！
but it's just a part of them! A partial showcase. Can you see?
ではまず一つ目は、こちら！ジャジャン！
Then, first of all, this one! Ta-da!
これさ、ちょっとこのね、天才だろこれ、ちょっと天才すぎる
Look at this, man, this is genius, it's just too brilliant.
こちらですね、なんか、あのー、みこが馬に乗ってるやつ！
This one here is the one where Miko is riding a horse!
すごな、よくシルエットからこんな書き起こしができたな、天才、天才なのか？
Incredible, how did they draw this from just a silhouette? A genius?
はい、いやこの発想はなかったなー
Yeah, man, I never would've thought of this.
で今回はね、やはり3Dだから、このね予想もね、3Dで、
And this time, because it's in 3D, Miko is doing things
3Dでしかできないことみこやってのける、あにゃはろー
with these predictions that only 3D can do. Ah, nyahharo.
う、う、どう？乗ってる、みこの手に、よ、よしよしよし
Um, um, how is it? I'm riding. On Miko's hand. There, there.
おおー、本当に似合ってるな、どう？お胸が出ちゃう
Ooh, it really suits me. How about it? My chest is popping out.
シュールだなこれ、こんなふうになるんですね、3Dのお披露目、
This is so surreal. So this is how it turns out for a 3D reveal,
お披露目からの、このね予想紹介はこんなふうになるんだなー、
doing a prediction showcase after the reveal like this...
天才やなー。発想の天才。
what a genius. A genius of ideas.
いや発想の天才ですね、ありがとうございます。
Yeah, they're a genius of ideas. Thank you very much.
あのこれね、実はお母さんもマリちゃんも好きって言ってました
Actually, my mom and Mari-chan said they liked this one too.
じゃあ次！よいしょ、じゃあこちらですね、はい！
Okay, next! Heave-ho, then it's this one, yes!
では続いてこちら、あ、お、お、はい！タラーン！
Then, moving on to this one... ah, oh, oh, yes! Ta-da!
対マグマ新衣装。まあみこにはよくマグマに突っ込んだり
Anti-magma new outfit. Well, Miko often plunges into magma
マグマに溶かされたりしますからね
or gets melted by magma, after all.
やばないこれ？これもよく、これもよくね、
Isn't this crazy? This one too, how were they able to
あのシルエットから想像ができたなー
imagine this from that silhouette?
はあ。
Haa.
なんかね、ちょっとね、おしめから見えてる紐がね、あるんですけど、
So, you see, there's a string visible from the diapers,
これをね、全面に持ってくるっていうね、すごい、いい発想だ。
but bringing that to the front is such a great idea.
消火器ということでね。
And it even has a fire extinguisher.
はい。あ、ここちょっと、これできない。これはできないな、こうか。
Okay. Ah, wait, I can't do this part. I can't do this... like this?
お。はい。こちらも、お、消火器だ。
Oh. Right. This one has a fire extinguisher too.
おおー、いいん。ちょっと欲しいっすけどね、これ。
Oh, nice. I actually kind of want this.
普通にあの別ゲー届きませんか？
Can't this just be delivered to another game?
あ、見て、すごい、八代目って書いてある。これエリトラじゃない？
Ah, look, amazing, it says "8th Generation". Isn't this an Elytra?
おー！
Whoa!
新衣装で無理やりエリトラを実装してもらうっていうね。
Forcing an Elytra into the new outfit, huh.
これ神ですね。
This is god-tier.
いいなー欲しいなー、ちょっとマイクラで欲しいわ、これ。
I like it, I want it. I really want this in Minecraft.
はい、じゃあ続いて、お衣装、よいしょ。こちらですね。
Okay, moving on to the next outfit. Here it is.
デデデン。
*Drumroll*
さあ、続いては、あ、おふろネタじゃないぞ。
Now, next... Oh, it's not a bath joke.
シュン。わあ！エッチだ！見てみんな。
*Swish* Whoa! It's sexy! Look, everyone.
あ、ちょっと、なんかも自分の胸を揉んでるかのような。あ、やばいやばいやばい。
Wait, it looks like I'm rubbing my own chest. Oh, no, no, no.
すごい！
Amazing!
かわいい！ちょっと露出度が高めな感じですね、なんかお姉さん。
So cute! The exposure is a bit high. It feels like a big sister.
いや、これを採用するのか？ホロライブラインを超えていないのか？
Wait, are we really using this? Hasn't it crossed the Hololive line?
超えてない？このぐらいなら。はい、組み合わせてみましょう。
Hasn't it? If it's just this much... Okay, let's try combining them.
お、あ、すごい。ハマり具合すごい。すごくない？みんな見て。
Oh, wow. It fits perfectly. Isn't it amazing? Everyone, look.
どうかな？
How is it?
あれ？みこのおへそが見えてて、でっかいお姉さん。お姉さんですよ皆さん。
Huh? You can see Miko's belly button. A tall big sister. I'm a big sister, everyone.
にゃっはろー、にゃっはろー、ママだよ。
Nyahallo, nyahallo. It's Mama.
うい。
Yeah.
あ、いいですね、こちら素晴らしいね。かわいい。正統派という感じでね。
Ah, this is nice. This is wonderful. Cute. It feels like a standard style.
お猫耳もね、かわいい。
The cat ears are cute too.
さあどんなふうになるんでしょうか。
Now, I wonder how it'll turn out.
じゃ、続いて、おいしょ、よいしょ。
Okay, moving on. Heave-ho.
あ、やば、時間がやばいよ。あ、また。
Ah, no, I'm running out of time. Ah, again...
うあ、違う、こう。はい！
Whoa, wait, like this. Okay!
部屋着だ！部屋着。イラストもかわいい。あ、にゃっはろー。
Loungewear! Loungewear. The illustration is cute too. Ah, Nyahallo.
みこが出てきてる。はい。
Miko is appearing. Right.
こちらは部屋着の衣装ですね。めっちゃかわいい。
This is a loungewear outfit. Super cute.
いい、しっぽが入っとんで。
Nice, it even has a tail.
イラストもかわいい。あ、猫入ってる.いい、これ金時のモチーフだね、フード。
The illustration is cute. Ah, a cat is in it. Nice, it's a Kintoki motif, the hood.
あ、お。いいのか。
Ah, oh. Is this okay?
これ自然にさ、頑張ってさ、スタッフのみんなとこうやってできるように調整したんだけど、
I worked hard with the staff to naturally adjust it so I could do this,
めちゃくちゃシュールだ。うちら何を頑張っていたんだろう。
but it's so surreal. I wonder what we were working so hard for.
すごい頑張ったん。この調整。これでも頑張ったんだ。にゅ。
I really worked hard on this adjustment. I really tried. Nyu.
かわいい、金時パイセンだね。金時っていうのはみこの式神だよ、みんな。
Cute. It's Kintoki-paisen. Kintoki is Miko's shikigami, everyone.
みこぴーの先輩です。かわいい。ポンポンもかわいい。
He's the senior to Miko-pi. So cute. The pompoms are cute too.
いい、いいな、みこもこういうのいいな。
Nice, I like this kind of thing too.
おいしょ。はい。続いて。
Heave-ho. Okay. Next.
おいしょ。じゃ、ジャン！
Heave-ho. Well then, ta-da!
あらま！これは白、白無垢っぽい予想。
My goodness! This is a shiro... shiromuku-like prediction.
お嫁だね、お嫁。お嫁のみこ。
A bride, a bride. Miko as a bride.
いいんじゃないこれ、ちょっと。またお姉さんだね。
Isn't this nice? A bit... it's a big sister again.
いつかみこも、ね、みこぴーもらってくれるんだろお前らは。
Someday Miko... right, Miko-pi? You guys will take me as your bride, right?
な。これがみこの嫁の衣装だ。
Right. This is Miko's bridal outfit.
お、今まだ似合わないかもしれんが、いつか、いつかみこも似合うような、
Ah, it might not suit me yet, but someday... someday I'll be a...
素敵なレディになるんだ。
wonderful lady it suits.
お、まだ許してくれないみたいだ。
Oh, looks like they won't allow it yet.
はい、めっちゃかわいいね。いい、いい、これ萌えます。
Okay. It's super cute. Nice, nice, this is so moe.
あ、お、この髪型めっちゃいいな、この髪型。
Oh, this hairstyle is great. This hairstyle.
よいしょ。続いて、次。はい。
Heave-ho. Moving on, next. Okay.
あ、お、何でだ！順番間違えた！ちょっと最初に持ってくるべきだった！
Ah, oh, why! I got the order wrong! I should have brought this out first!
これ！おい！今いい感じだったのに何で。
This! Hey! It was going so well, why...!
ちょっとこんなとこ言っちゃいけないけど、古代のロマンセットですね。
I shouldn't say this, but it's the "Ancient Romance" set.
これは。でもこれ一番のハマり具合なんだよな、これ。
This is... but this one fits me the best, doesn't it?
すごい、あれだけど。これ一番ハマってる気がする。
It's pretty... that, but I feel like this one fits best.
あ、だって同じ顔してるもんな。同じ顔してんだよな。
I mean, we have the same face. We really have the same face.
う、ちょっと怖い、怖い.バーチャル怖いよ、バーチャル怖すぎ。
Uh. A bit scary, scary. Virtual is scary, it's too scary.
みこ頑張れ、みこ頑張れ！
Miko, do your best! Miko, do your best!
うわ～んにゃっはろ～！
Uwan-nyahallo~!
なんか前衛的なデザインですね、これは。
This is quite an avant-garde design, isn't it?
パリコレにどうでしょうか？パリコレに。
How about for Paris Fashion Week? For Paris Fashion Week.
いけるんじゃないか？
Maybe it could work?
そのくらい前衛的なファッションですね。
It's that kind of avant-garde fashion.
これかもしんない、ワンチャンな。
This might be it, just maybe.
さくらみこ新衣装お披露目LIVE
SAKURA MIKO NEW OUTFIT LIVE
そんなわけないだろう！
No way that's it!
続いて･･･よいしょ。
Next... up we go.
あ、これが最後。ダダン！
Ah, this is the last one. Ta-dah!
ちょっとセンシティブ･･･
A bit sensitive...
センシティブすぎるよ！大丈夫かこれ？
It's too sensitive! Is this okay?
はい、これはね･･･
Yes, this is...
･･･一番センシティブな新衣装予想ですね。
...the most sensitive new outfit prediction.
ちょっと見せていいのかな？
Is it okay to show this?
横ね･･･これもホロライブサマーだね、ギリギリだね。
The side... this is also like Hololive Summer, barely safe.
パ･･･パンツが･･･
The... the underwear is...
ダメでしょうこれは！
This is not okay!
これはダメだ、これはダメだ。
This is bad, this is bad.
ダメ。
No.
これはね、やばい。
This is dangerous.
あの･･･ちょっと出てる･･･出てるね。
Um... it's sticking out a bit... it's sticking out.
なかなかにセンシティブです。
It's quite sensitive.
しゅ！こちらで･･･隠して。
Shu! I'll hide it... with this.
あやややや！お！あ、ダメだ～！
Aya-ya-ya-ya! Oh! Ah, it's no good~!
はい、でもすごい可愛いデザイン、ありがとうございます！
Well, it's a very cute design, thank you very much!
にゃ～すごいね。
Nya~ amazing.
みんなすごいな、発想が豊かだ。よいしょ。
Everyone's great, such rich imaginations. Up we go.
ということで･･･はぁ～
So... phew~
ちょっとたっぷりやってしまったが。
I spent quite a bit of time on that.
はい、ということで。
Alright then.
それでは早速ね、お待ちかねの･･･
Without further ado, the long-awaited...
･･･ライブパートが始まります！
...live performance part is starting!
あの、今日ね、ゲストもね、呼んでいるので･･･
Um, I've invited guests today too, so...
･･･誰が来るのかな？楽しみにしていてください！
...who will it be? Please look forward to it!
それでは、ゲストパート、レッツゴー！
Now then, the guest part, let's go!
パッとパッと晴れやかに
Sparkle, sparkle, radiantly
咲かせましょう 花のように
Let's make them bloom like flowers
後ろは少しを 踏み出す力と
The background is a little bit of power to step forward
弱気な心を開ける 魔法のキー
The magic key that opens a timid heart
それでも一歩 勢いよく跳ねて
Even so, take a step and leap with vigor
始まる夢は
The dream that begins...
本気の
...is a serious...
夢は
...dream...
胸は
...my heart...
どんな形
What kind of shape?
踊れや踊れ
Dance, oh dance
散らさないでもっともっと一緒に
Don't let them scatter, let's be together more and more
数えたい
I want to count them
新しい景色
A new scenery
いろはにほ パッとパッと晴れやかに
I-ro-ha-ni-ho, sparkle, sparkle, radiantly
ハイ！
Hai!
咲かせましょう 花のように
Let's make them bloom like flowers
ハイハイ！
Hai hai!
これからの君が見たい
I want to see the future you
いろはにほ パッとパッと晴れやかに
I-ro-ha-ni-ho, sparkle, sparkle, radiantly
ハイ！
Hai!
咲かせる思いは常ならぬ
The feelings I make bloom are not ordinary
だって乙女の花は
Because a maiden's flower...
風任せなのと 呟いてみた
...is left to the wind, I tried whispering
乙女心さ
It's a maiden's heart
迷ってるだけなら何も起こらない
If you're just hesitating, nothing will happen
強気で行くんだと瞳で語るよ
I'll tell you with my eyes that I'm going in strong
そしたらさおいで 明日がピカピカと
Then come along, tomorrow is sparkling
輝く夢の
Of a shining dream...
本当さ夢の
...truly of a dream...
色に変わる
...it changes into colors
歌えや歌え
Sing, oh sing
浮かされながらずっとずっと一緒に
While being carried away, let's be together forever
遊びたい
I want to play
さくら色ハーモニー
Sakura-colored harmony
散りぬるを サッとサッと流れてく
Scattering away, it flows quickly
ハイ！
Hai!
泡沫の花の香り
The scent of transient flowers
ハイハイ！
Hai hai!
いつまでも君といたい
I want to be with you forever
散りぬるを サッとサッと流れてく
Scattering away, it flows quickly
出会いと別れに酔いもせず
Without being intoxicated by meetings and partings
そっと見つめ合って君の気配を
Gently looking at each other, I want to...
感じていたい
...feel your presence
乙女の願い
A maiden's wish
踊れや今こんなに嬉しくて
Dance now, I'm so happy
踊れほらこんなに嬉しくて
Dance, look, I'm so happy
気分次第で騒げ目覚めた
Make some noise according to your mood, I've woken up
歌えや今こんなに楽しくて
Sing now, I'm having so much fun
歌えほらこんなに楽しくて
Sing, look, I'm having so much fun
ずっともっと一緒に遊びたい
I want to play together much more!
気持ちが奏でる
My feelings play...
さくら色ハーモニー
...a cherry-blossom colored harmony.
いろはにほ　ぱぱとぱーとはれやかに
The colors and scents are gaily scattered...
咲かせましょう　花のよに
...let's make them bloom like flowers.
これからの日々が見たい
I want to see the days to come.
いろはにほ　ぱぱとぱーとはれやかに
The colors and scents are gaily scattered...
咲かせる想いは　つねならむ
...the blooming feelings are ever-changing.
だって　乙女道は　風まかせだと
Because the maiden's path is at the mercy of the wind...
呟いてみた
...so it seems it's being whispered.
乙女の心さ
It's a maiden's heart.
色まにをえど
The colors and scents are...
散りたくないな
I don't want them to scatter.
はい！ということでね
Alright! And so...
一番最初のゲストは、余様たんとねねちに来てもらいました！
...our very first guests are Ayame-chan and Nene-chi!
イエーイ！やったやったー！
Yay! We did it, we did it!
いや、この組み合わせはちょっと意外ですね。
Man, this combination is a bit unexpected, isn't it?
ね、なかなかない。
Right, you don't see it often.
みこ、初めてじゃない？
Miko, isn't this the first time?
初めて。そうかもしれない。
The first time. That might be true.
誘わせていただきましたね。
I took the liberty of inviting you.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございます、逆にね。来てもらえてね。
No, thank you for coming.
どう、みんな可愛いでしょ？
How is it? Everyone's cute, right?
結構並びいいよね。
The lineup is pretty good, isn't it?
ね、ちょっとシナジーが…
Yeah, there's a bit of synergy...
シナジーがね、あるかなと思って呼ばせていただいたんですけど。
I thought there might be some synergy, so I invited you.
画角可愛すぎる。
This shot is too cute.
可愛い！めちゃ可愛い！イエーイ！
Cute! So cute! Yay!
ということで今日はね、みこの新衣装お披露目ということでね
Anyway, since today is the reveal of Miko's new outfit...
ちょっとお二人に、なんと、新衣装の予想も書いてもらったんですよ！
...I actually had you two draw your predictions for the new outfit!
書きましたよ！
We drew them!
じゃあ、ちょっと持ってきてもらおうかな。
Well then, could you bring them over?
よいこらだ。よいこらだ。よい、よい、よい、よい。
Over here. Over here. Yo-ho, yo-ho.
どっちからいこうかな。どうする？
Which one should we start with? What should we do?
じゃあ余様さん…待って、余の、余の…
Well then, Ayame-san... Wait, mine is...
待って、余のやつなくなった。余の埋まった！
Wait, mine is gone. Mine got buried!
余の埋まった。あれ？じゃあ、ちょっとねねちからいこうかな。
Mine got buried. Huh? Well, let's start with Nene-chi.
オーケー！ゴー！いいの？こっちでいいの？
Okay! Go! Is it okay? Is it okay here?
うん、たぶん、きっと変わってるでしょう。
Yeah, it'll probably change.
はい、ということでねねちが書いてくれました、このシルエットのやつ。
Alright, so Nene-chi drew this based on the silhouette.
こんな感じにしました！
I made it like this!
お、いいじゃないの。
Oh, that's not bad.
なんか和風の猫耳メイドみたいな感じかなって。
I thought it might be something like a Japanese-style cat-ear maid.
お、いいですね。え、これ髪型は？
Oh, that's nice. And this hairstyle?
髪型は…おかっぱみたいな感じ？
The hairstyle... is like a bob cut?
ちょっとクレオパトラみたいな…
A bit like Cleopatra...
まあそうだね、猫耳が付いてるからね。
Well yeah, since it has cat ears.
で、これ絶対に頭にお花付いてるだろうなと思って。
And I thought there would definitely be a flower on the head.
お、シルエット予想、完璧。
Oh, the silhouette prediction is perfect.
でも、当たってるところもありけり？
But, there are some parts that are correct?
ホント？かすってる？
Really? Am I close?
あ、みこ出た出た、見て見て。ボーン！
Oh, Miko appeared, look look. Boing!
お、これあれじゃない？顔だけ出た！
Oh, isn't that... Just the face came out!
嘘！顔ハメみたいな。
No way! It's like a face-fitting board.
あ！やめてこと！やめてこと！
Ah! Stop that! Stop that!
いや、可愛い。メイド服みたいな感じ。
But it's cute. It's like a maid outfit.
そうそうそう。なんか和風のメイドさんみたいな感じで。
Right, right. Like a Japanese-style maid.
露出もあり。
With some skin showing too.
いや、いいですね。
Wow, that's nice.
ま、ちょっとシルエットが結構分かりづらいからね、これは予想し甲斐がある。
Well, the silhouette is pretty hard to decipher, so it's worth predicting.
予想し甲斐があった。
It was worth predicting.
あ、直りました。
Ah, it's fixed.
やった！直りましたよ！
Yay! It's fixed!
じゃあ、はい。余がこんな感じに予想…
Alright, so here's Ayame's prediction...
あ、こんな感じです。
Ah, it's like this.
ちょっとねねちと違うね。
It's a bit different from Nene-chi's.
そうだね、リボンの感じはちょっと似てると思う。
Yeah, I think the ribbon part is a bit similar.
確かに確かに。なんかちょっとポンチョ？ポンチョっぽいね。
True, true. It's a bit like a poncho? Poncho-esque.
ポンチョっぽいかなって思って、ちょっと羽織ってるんじゃないかって。
I thought it might be poncho-esque, like she's wearing something over it.
可愛い。個人的な好みで腕にリボン付けておきましたけど。
Cute. I added ribbons to the arms as a personal preference.
可愛い可愛い。こんな感じにしてみました。
Cute, cute. I made it like this.
ま、でもどちらも可愛いですね。頭出るね。
Well, they're both cute. The head pops out.
お、似合う似合う！
Oh, it suits you!
可愛い！イエーイ！つい出ちゃっていますけど。
Cute! Yay! It's kind of peeking out.
もしくは無いところも…予想外…
Or maybe parts that aren't there... unexpected...
ありがとうございます、書いていただいてね。
Thank you for drawing them for me.
ということで、ま、これはお二人もこの後のお披露目をお楽しみにということで。
So, I hope you two will look forward to the reveal afterwards.
お楽しみに！どれがホントなんだろう？
Looking forward to it! Which one is the real one?
まだ見せてないからね。お楽しみですね。
I haven't shown it yet. Something to look forward to.
はい！ということで、ねねちとあやめ様に来てもらいました。
Yes! So, I had Nene-chi and Ayame-sama come over.
あり〜！ありがとう〜！
Thank you! Thanks!
ありがとうございました。じゃあ、次の曲行きます！
Thank you very much. Now, on to the next song!
ありがとね〜。
Thank you.
頑張ってね〜。
Good luck.
バイバイ〜。
Bye-bye.
それじゃ、次の曲行くぞ〜！
Well then, on to the next song!
色づく想い 刹那 百花繚乱花吹雪
Coloured feelings, a momentary profusion of flowers, a blizzard of petals
百花繚乱我若吹雪
作詞・作曲：武田将弥 (Dream Monster)
Hyakka Ryouran Waga Hakusetsu
Lyrics/Composition: Masaya Takeda (Dream Monster)
パッと咲いて散った花は 終末を告げてく
Flowers that bloomed and fell in an instant tell of the end
その時は待てど暮らせど 事は進まず
No matter how long I wait, things don't progress
そっと触れてしまった 胸の内の暖かさを
The warmth inside my chest that I gently touched
初めてのこの気持ちだけ 抱きしめていた
I was just holding onto this first-time feeling
暁 交わした約束は
The promise exchanged at dawn
本物だってきっと 信じてる
I'm sure it's real, I believe
いろはにほへと の花に 魅せられた 蝶々たち
Butterflies captivated by the flowers of the world
あぁ はらり はらり はらり 落ちる花と舞い踊れ
Ah, dance with the flowers falling flutteringly
若よ誰そ でも想い 言の葉に込めてみた
Who goes there? But I tried to put my feelings into words
誰も皆 憧れる 現世のことわりよ
The truth of this transient world that everyone longs for
色づく想い 刹那 百花繚乱花吹雪
Coloured feelings, a momentary profusion of flowers, a blizzard of petals
ふっと吹き消した 夜を灯す 月明かりに
In the moonlight that lights up the night I suddenly blew out
曖昧な心が揺れて 声は震わす
My ambiguous heart wavers, my voice trembles
もっと触れたくて 夢を辿る指先まで
Wanting to touch more, right down to the fingertips following the dream
いつか褪せた形を 忘れかけていた
I was starting to forget the form that faded away one day
浮世の波に たゆたう時
When swaying in the waves of the fleeting world
うたかたの夢は 弾けてく
The transient dreams burst open
有為の奥山に 荒れる想いたちは 純情も
The feelings raging in the deep mountains of existence, even innocence
そのなれの果てに心揺らめき歌は告げるか
Does the heart waver and the song tell of its ruined state?
浅き夢見じと想い 踏み込むこの世界は
Entering this world with the thought of not dreaming shallow dreams
誰も皆 憧れる 現世のことわりよ
The truth of this transient world that everyone longs for
色づく想い 刹那 百花繚乱花吹雪
Coloured feelings, a momentary profusion of flowers, a blizzard of petals
ひふみ数えて
Counting one, two, three
ここにおいで
Come here
暁 交わした約束は
The promise exchanged at dawn
本物だってきっと 信じてる
I'm sure it's real, I believe
いろはにほへと の花に 魅せられた 蝶々たち
Butterflies captivated by the flowers of the world
あぁ はらり はらり はらり 落ちる花と舞い踊れ
Ah, dance with the flowers falling flutteringly
若よ誰そ でも想い 言の葉に込めてみた
Who goes there? But I tried to put my feelings into words
誰も皆 憧れる 現世のことわりよ
The truth of this transient world that everyone longs for
色づく想い 刹那 百花繚乱花吹雪
Coloured feelings, a momentary profusion of flowers, a blizzard of petals
風に舞う 乙女の純情 咲き誇れ
A maiden's innocence dancing in the wind, bloom in full glory
はーい！
Haaay!
ということで。
So.
あれ？なんか一人違うな。
Huh? One of us is different.
あれ？なんか...あれ？
Huh? Something's... eh?
え、なんか違う？違くないよ！
Eh, something's different? It's not!
どうも皆さん、いろはにほへと みこはばみこです！
Hello everyone, I'm Irohanihoheto Miko-haba-miko!
あれ、なんか違うな。
Huh, something's different.
なんか違くないか？
Isn't something different?
巫女だよ！
I'm a shrine maiden!
余白さ、お前どこやったんだよ！
Yohaku (Ayame), where did you put her!
どこやったんだよ！
Where did you put her!
ちょっとね、あの、やっぱり憧れを持ってましてね。
Well, you see, I've always admired it.
みこもほら、神社だしさ。
Miko is from a shrine too, you know.
まあ確かにそれはある。
Well, that's true.
巫女さんだしさ。
And a shrine maiden.
確かにな。
True.
鬼ではないけどさ。
I'm not an ogre, though.
親和性はあるかなと思って、ちょっと叶えさせていただきましたね。
But I thought there was an affinity, so I decided to fulfill my wish.
まあまあまあ。
Well, well.
そうだね。
That's right.
さっきまであやめちゃんもいたんだよ。
Ayame-chan was here just now too.
そうだね。
That's right.
あやめちゃん言ってね。
Ayame-chan, go ahead.
さあ、あやめをどこにやったんだー！
Now, what did you do with Ayame?!
ということで、今日は新衣装のお披露目ということで。
So, today is the new outfit reveal.
はい！はい！
Yes! Yes!
みこ、このあと新衣装お披露目するんですけど。
I'll be revealing my new outfit after this.
いぇーい！楽しみだ！楽しみだ！
Yay! Can't wait! Can't wait!
どうなるのかな？ね、どうなるんだろうね。
I wonder how it'll look. Yeah, I wonder.
まあ、お楽しみなんですけど。
Well, look forward to it.
さっきもね、あやめちゃんとあとみおちに新衣装の予想書いてもらってたんですよ。
Earlier, I had Ayame-chan and Mio-chi draw their predictions for the new outfit.
はいはい。
Right, right.
でお二人に書いていただきましたよね。
And the two of you wrote them, didn't you?
書かせていただきました！
We certainly did!
やったー！ということで、じゃあ持ってきてもらおうかな。
Hooray! So, let's have you bring them out.
持ってきましょっか。お、持ってきましょう。
Let's go get them. Oh, let's get them.
お楽しみだな。
I'm looking forward to it.
よいしょ、よいしょ。よだだよ。よだだよ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho. It's Yoda. It's Yoda.
よだじゃないだろ、こんな時に！
It's not Yoda, not at a time like this!
違うだ。何も考えておらんかったんか。
No way. Were you not thinking about anything?
何も考えてなかったｗ
I wasn't thinking at all lol
ということで、はい。来たー！
So, yes. They're here!
いいですか。じゃあ。はいはい。お、いい感じ。カラフルですね。
Ready? Then... Yes, yes. Oh, nice. Very colorful.
はい。
Yes.
あれ？なんかすごい露出がすごいな。
Wait, there's a lot of skin showing.
なんか露出が多いほうがいいかなと思って。
I thought more exposure would be better.
なるほど。これ、てるてる坊主？
I see. Is this a Teru Teru Bozu?
てるてる坊主あった。え、すごい。二人とも同じ考えなんだね。
There's a Teru Teru Bozu. Wow, you both had the same idea.
露出の違いはあるけど、本当だ。ちょっと似てる感じ。
The amount of exposure differs, but it's true. They look a bit similar.
雨降ってるね。なんか被ってるのかなと思って。
It's raining. I thought maybe you were wearing something.
そう、で、下になんか水着だけど、下はちょっと水着センシティブだから...
Yeah, and beneath it's a swimsuit, but since the bottom is a bit sensitive...
くびれね。のぞみこだよ。みこだよ。
The waistline. It's Nozomiko. It's Miko.
みこだよ。みこだよ。
It's Miko. It's Miko.
なんかビート板も出てきてますけど。
There are even kickboards appearing.
で、腕になんかみこち、ちょっとペがナーフされてる気がする...
And on the arms... Miko-chi, I feel like your chest has been nerfed...
ナーフされてるｗ 戦いそうだな。
It's nerfed lol. Looks like she's ready for a fight.
でもこれ腕にビート板付けてる。
But she has kickboards on her arms.
泳げねえからｗ
Because I can't swim lol
ありがてえ機能ではあるけどｗ
It's a helpful feature though lol
なるほど。着てみてもらってじゃあ。
I see. Let's have you try wearing it then.
着てみました。んんん...
I've put it on. Hmmm...
あ、いいねいいね！いいじゃんいいじゃん！
Oh, nice, nice! That looks great!
ホロライブサマー感あるんじゃない？
Doesn't it have a Hololive Summer vibe?
もしかして、これでホロライブサマーある？
Maybe this is for Hololive Summer?
あるかもしれない。
It might be.
さすがにちょっとあれだね、ビート板腕につけてるホロライブサマーはちょっと...
But a Hololive Summer with kickboards on the arms is a bit...
ダメかな？
Is it no good?
ダメじゃないけどさ、ちょっと良くないか。
It's not bad, but it's not quite right.
やっぱり露出はちょっとね、したい気持ちもあるから。まあ。
I do feel like showing some skin. Well.
ああ、そうなんですか。
Oh, is that so?
みこ、後ろから入ってるちょろおのが酸素ボンベの管かなみたいな。
Miko, is that thing coming from the back an oxygen tank tube?
違うわｗ。酸素ボンベだったの？
No way lol. Was it an oxygen tank?
酸素ボンベの管なのかなと思いながら。はい、ありがとうございました。
I was wondering if it was an oxygen tank tube. Okay, thank you very much.
で、ミオのが。
And Mio's...
うちはね、これ。「雨でも平気だにぇ」。
Mine is this. "I'm fine even in the rain."
「雨でも平気だにぇ」。かわいい。みこぴー好きそうだね。
"I'm fine even in the rain." Cute. Mikopi would probably like this.
これはね、あの、幼稚園児がよく着てる黄色のカッパを着せました。
This is... I put you in a yellow raincoat that preschoolers often wear.
カッパだ。猫耳もついてるのかな。
A raincoat. Does it have cat ears too?
かわいい。ちょっと黄色の長靴も履いて。
Cute. And you're wearing yellow boots.
そうなんだよ、ちゃんと長靴も履いてて。多分猫の尻尾なのかなと思って付けました。
That's right, you're wearing boots. I added what I think is a cat tail.
長靴もｗ。はい。
Boots too lol. Yes.
ほら、あれだね、信号渡るとき用の黄色い旗も欲しいね。
Hey, we need that yellow flag for crossing the street too.
あ、そうだね。雨でも平気だね。みこち、かわいい。
Ah, true. Fine even in the rain. Miko-chi, you're cute.
これかわいいね。これかもしれない、正解。
This is cute. This might be it, the correct answer.
もしかしてこれなのかな？どんぴしゃかも。これから梅雨になるしね。
Could it be this? Might be spot on. Rainy season is coming up.
確かに、確かに。この季節はそういうことなの？
True, true. Is that what it's like this season?
いや、さすがに季節読んじゃいましたよね。
Well, as expected, I read the season.
ああ、そういうことか。まあ確かにね、これもあるかもしれないね。
Oh, I see. Well, it's possible this could be it too.
正解に限りなく近いかもしれない。でもめちゃかわいい。
It might be very close to the correct answer. But it's so cute.
ね、でもホロライブサマーも諦めたくないね。
Yeah, but I don't want to give up on Hololive Summer either.
サマーも諦めたくない。ホロライブ梅雨もあるかも。
Don't want to give up on Summer. Maybe there's a Hololive Rainy Season.
梅雨ｗ。梅雨ｗ。
Rainy season lol. Rainy season lol.
すごいですね。ありがとうございました、わざわざ楽屋で書いていただいて。
That's amazing. Thank you so much for taking the time to draw these in the dressing room.
いえいえ。
Not at all.
まあこのあとね、お楽しみなお披露目があるので、ぜひ見ててください。
Well, there's an exciting reveal coming up, so please look forward to it.
楽しみにしてるよ！頑張れー！
We're looking forward to it! Good luck!
正解かな、これがね。
I wonder if this is the right answer.
いや、今後もね、ちょっと新メンバーとしてさ、あやふみ組の中に。
No, in the future too... as a new member, in the Aya-Fumi group.
みこも入れてもらって。入ろう入ろう！入りなよ、入れて！
Please include Miko too. Let's join! Come on in, let her in!
あ、入っちゃうｗ。ありがとうございます。
Oh, I'm in lol. Thank you.
それじゃ、お披露目だ！
Now, for the reveal!
あ、着替えてこん...
Ah, I'm going to change...
あ、まだ着替えないんだった。バイバーイ！
Ah, I'm not changing yet. Bye-bye!
ああ ゆめかまぼろしか
Ah, is it a dream or an illusion?
さあさ こよいおきかせたまふは
Now, what I shall have you hear tonight is
しゅらとちる ものがたり
A story of a carnage that scatters
拍手喝采歌合
作詞・作曲：ryo
Hakushu Kassai Utaawase
Lyrics/Composition: ryo
拍手喝采歌合
作詞・作曲：ryo
Applause & Cheers Song-Off
Lyrics/Composition: ryo
あー、浅き夢見し　うたたねの中で
Ah, in the midst of a shallow dream, while dozing...
人の定めは　かくも儚きもの
The fate of man is such a fragile thing.
己が望んだならずばな
If I myself am a rogue flower...
相容れぬは許すまじ
Being incompatible is unforgivable.
この世は泡沫
This world is transient bubbles,
流るるままに
flowing as it will.
十余り二つ　酔いもせず
Ten and two, without getting drunk,
見るは夢か　幻か
what I see is it a dream or an illusion?
重ねても叶わぬまでは
Until it no longer comes true no matter how often repeated,
ただ弱く　あだ美し
it's just weak and transiently beautiful.
仇桜　夜明けに散る　灯し火　ずっと
Transient cherry blossoms, falling at dawn, a light forever...
勝つも負けるも　時の運ならば
If winning or losing is all down to luck,
覚悟を決めて　いざ推して参れ
prepare yourself, and let us advance!
人は流れて　どこへ行く
People flow on, where do they go?
涙流れて　どこへ行く
Tears flow on, where do they go?
君を悲しと　思っても
Even if I think of you as sorrowful,
今日を限りと　決めた祈りよ
it's a prayer that has decided today is the limit!
散るは花　恋い心
Falling are the flowers, the longing heart,
叶わぬなら　いっそこの世は泡沫
if it won't come true, then this world is better as foam,
流るるままに
flowing as it will.
十余り二つ　狂いもせず
Ten and two, without going mad,
見るは鬼か　人の子か
what I see is it a demon or a child of man?
重ねても食えても
Even if repeated, even if consumed,
手放さぬ　仇なし世
I won't let go of this transient world.
仇の縁　雨の月さえ　ほら
Transient ties, look, even the moon in the rain...
あー、浅き夢見し　うたたねの中で
Ah, in the midst of a shallow dream, while dozing...
人の定めは
The fate of man is...
かくも儚きもの
...such a fragile thing.
回レ！雪月花
作詞・作曲：ヒゲドライバー
Spin! Snow, Moon, and Flowers
Lyrics/Composition: Hige Driver
ほい！
Hoi!
いいよ！
Nice!
ぱん！
Pan!
これよりご覧いただきますのは　か弱き者たちの永点ずる
What you are about to see is the eternal dance of the weak.
時代は常に進月歩　老若男女
The times are always evolving, regardless of age or gender.
意見は完全懲悪　悪者の類　それそれ
Opinion is the punishment of evil, those villains, there there.
何でも本に振るだけで楽しいの
Anything is fun just by flipping through the book.
どんなってこんな公問答
What kind of public debate is this?
ぱん！
Pan!
どこからともなく現れ出てくる　とか言っちゃって心酔
Appearing out of nowhere, or so I say, fascinated.
チャンスを待ったら一日千秋　追い越せれば途法精査
Waiting for a chance feels like an eternity, if I can overtake, it's a careful search.
時代は常に変幻万化　人の心を和え返しても
Times are always changing, even if you try to blend human hearts.
本気でそんなこと言ってんの？
Are you seriously saying that?
戻りももし子
Even coming back...
あー、巡り巡って夜の街
Ah, going round and round through the night streets.
君は愛づらし　天出す雨も
You are beloved, even the rain falling from the sky.
はー！回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Ha! Spin spin spin spin spin spin spin spin spin!
華麗に雅に散るように
Like falling elegantly and gracefully.
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ！
Spin spin spin spin spin spin spin spin spin!
髪も振り乱して
With hair flying wildly.
お祭り　昨日今日と明日と明後日と
The festival—yesterday, today, tomorrow, and the day after,
この宴は続く
this feast continues.
踊れ歌え一心不乱に回レ
Dance and sing, spin with all your might,
今宵は雪月花！
tonight is the Snow, Moon, and Flowers!
はなればなれになるはずがなくて
There's no way we'll be separated.
呑めや歌えやのどんちゃん騒ぎ
Drinking, singing, and a wild party.
常世の物も千客万来
Even things from the afterlife are coming in droves.
四方八方 誘っちゃおう
Let's invite everyone from all directions.
乗るか反るかの一攫千金
Sink or swim for a get-rich-quick chance.
気が付いたら 絶対 絶命
Before I knew it, I was in a desperate situation.
魔法の手解き とことん
A magical introduction,
なってんの
all the way through.
桃 瞬き そして嗚呼
A peach-colored twinkle, and then, ah...
辿り辿るよ 夜の街
I'll wander through the night town.
迷い一つなく 踊り出す
Start dancing without a single doubt.
回れ回れ回れ回れ
Spin, spin, spin, spin,
回れ回れ回れ
spin, spin, spin...
風に花弁 散らすように
Like petals scattering in the wind.
回れ回れ回れ回れ
Spin, spin, spin, spin,
回れ回れ回れ
spin, spin, spin...
髪も振り乱して
Hair disheveled...
お祭り騒ぎ
Festival frenzy.
今日と明日と明後日と
Today, tomorrow, and the day after,
こんな宴は 続く
this feast will continue.
踊れ 歌え
Dance and sing,
一心不乱に回れ
spin with single-minded devotion.
今宵は雪月花
Tonight is the snow, moon, and flowers.
花でひとつ 独りでふたつ
One flower, alone for two,
手拍子 鳴らす
clapping hands.
風で三つ 四つ引き連れて
With the wind, bringing three and four,
鳴らす 鳴らす
clapping, clapping.
花でひとつ 独りでふたつ
One flower, alone for two,
手拍子 鳴らす
clapping hands.
風で三つ 四つ引き連れて
With the wind, bringing three and four,
鳴らす 鳴らす
clapping, clapping.
今だ！
Now!
回れ回れ回れ回れ
Spin, spin, spin, spin,
回れ回れ回れ
spin, spin, spin...
風に花弁 散らすように
Like petals scattering in the wind.
回れ回れ回れ回れ
Spin, spin, spin, spin,
回れ回れ回れ
spin, spin, spin...
髪も振り乱して
Hair disheveled...
お祭り騒ぎ
Festival frenzy.
今日と明日と明後日と
Today, tomorrow, and the day after,
こんな宴は 続く
this feast will continue.
踊れ 歌え
Dance and sing,
一心不乱に回れ
spin with single-minded devotion.
今宵は雪月花
Tonight is the snow, moon, and flowers.
水 木 金 土 日 月 火
Wed Thu Fri Sat Sun Mon Tue
はっ、はっ、はっ、はっ、はっ、はいやー！
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, hi-ya!
はい！ということで、皆さん！
All right! So, everyone!
にゃー！
Nya!
はい、ということで
So, as I was saying,
新衣装お披露目しました！
I've revealed my new outfit!
変身したよ！
I transformed!
どうですか？
How is it?
可愛い？
Is it cute?
どう？
How's it look?
どう？見て見て、ショートパンツなの！
How is it? Look, look, it's short pants!
見て、みんな念願の
Look, the long-awaited...
念願の紐が帰ってきたよ！
the long-awaited strings are back!
パンツ見えなければいいだろってことで
"As long as you can't see the underwear," so...
帰ってきたよ、やったー！
it's back! Yay!
どう？可愛い、みんな？
How is it? Is it cute, everyone?
ちょっとね、今回は
So, for this one,
あの、和ではあるんですけど
it's a Japanese style, but...
結構いろんなパターンがあって
there are actually quite a few patterns,
ちょっとシルエットとかね、違うでしょ？
and the silhouette is different, right?
予想できなかっただろ、にゃ！
You couldn't have predicted this, nya!
ぜひちょっとね、カッコいい
I also wanted some cool...
ちょっとカッコいいところもありつつ
some cool parts as well,
みこっぽい感じで
with a "Miko-like" feel,
仕立てていただきました。
and that's how it was tailored.
おしお先生、ありがとう！
Thank you, Oshio-sensei!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
今日、YouTubeくんが、あの、なんかポツポツだけど
YouTube is a bit stuttery today, but...
大丈夫かな？
is it okay?
大丈夫？ねえ、見えてるみんな？
Are you okay? Hey, can everyone see me?
あ、ありがとう！
Ah, thank you!
はい、で見え、尻尾、わかる？
Okay, and can you see the tail?
尻尾！
Tail!
尻尾もあるんだ、すごいでしょ？
There's also a tail, amazing right?
尻尾も生えたよ！
I grew a tail too!
イェーイ！
Yay!
そしてね、ちょっと最初は髪長かったけど
And although my hair was long at first,
見て、切ってみた！
look, I tried cutting it!
バーチャルだからね、切ったり生えたりできるんだ。
Since I'm virtual, I can cut it or grow it out.
どう？可愛い？
How is it? Is it cute?
あの、意外と前面の方は露出がなくて
Surprisingly, there's not much skin on the front,
あのね、だからちょっと
so, you know, I tried to...
露出も多めにしてみたよ。
show a bit more skin overall.
なんかちょっと戦いそうだよね。
Looks like I could fight in this.
あとね、見て、おへそ！
And look, my belly button!
あ、ちょっとボタン押し忘れていますが
Ah, I forgot to press the button, but...
どうかな？
what do you think?
恥ずかしいね、なんかここだけ見るとやばい
It's embarrassing. Looking at just this part is...
やばすぎる、なんかやばいな。
It's too much, kind of risky.
で、背中もね、ちゃんとね、クロス
And for the back, with these straps...
背中も見えるようにしてもらいました。
I had it made so you can see my back too.
やっぱ背中綺麗で、な、ないとな
I should definitely have a nice back view...
あ、ほら見て
Oh, look!
横も、いいな
Side view is good too.
わーい！
Yay!
わ、喜んでもらえて嬉しい。やったー！
I'm so glad you're happy. Yay!
はい、ということで
Okay, so...
まあね、まだまだありますから
Well, there's still more to come.
みんな最後まで見てってね、頑張ったから
So everyone, please watch until the end, I worked hard.
よろしくな、みんな
I'm counting on you, everyone.
よし、応援してみんな、おい、よろしく
Alright, cheer for me, everyone! Hey, counting on you.
頑張れって言ってね。頑張るよ
Say "Go for it!" I'll do my best.
はい、それでは、じゃあ次の曲、行きますか。頑張るぞ
Alright then, well, let's head to the next song. I'll do my best.
はい。それでは、次の曲、いくぞー！
Okay. Well then, here we go with the next song!
吉原ラメント
Yoshiwara Lament
江戸の街は 今日も深く 夜の帳 降りて行く
Edo city is once again deep tonight, as the veil of night descends.
鏡向いて 紅を引いて 応じるまま 受け入れるまま
Facing the mirror, applying red rouge, responding just as told, accepting just as told.
橙色 輝く花 憧れてた 望んでいた
The orange-colored shining flowers I admired and yearned for.
いつの間にか 藍色の花 けれど私 安くないわ
Before I knew it, indigo flowers... but I'm not cheap.
まことは、ただ一人のどなたかのためだけに咲いていたかったのだけれど
The truth is, I wanted to bloom for just one person, but...
運命はわっちの自由を奪い、そいで、歯車を回して行くのでありんす
Fate stole my freedom and then kept turning the gears.
偽りだらけの恋愛をして 私を丸ごと 飲んで
Engagement in love full of lies, swallow me whole.
哀しいくらいに感じた 振りの 吉原 今日は雨
The Yoshiwara where I pretended to feel even sadly... today, it's raining.
貴方様 どうか私を 買っていただけないでしょうか
You there, would you please buy me?
咲き出す 傘の胸に 濡れる
Blooming in the chest of an umbrella, getting wet.
私は、雨
I am the rain.
行き交う群れ 賑わう声が 犇めき合い 縺れ合い
The passing crowds, the bustling voices, jostling and tangling together.
願うことは どうかいつか 鳥籠の外 連れ出して
My only wish is for you to someday take me out of this birdcage.
まことは、いく宛てなどなくなってしまいんしたのだけれど
The truth is, I've run out of places to go, but...
この籠の中から見える景色だけは、わっちをいつの時も 癒してくれるのでありんす
Only the scenery seen from within this cage heals me at all times.
偽りだらけの恋愛をして 私を丸ごと 飲んで
Engagement in love full of lies, swallow me whole.
私 抱いた花びら 濡れる葛藤に 震わめ
The petals I held, trembling in the wetting conflict, rain.
貴方様 どうか私と 一夜限りの戯れを
You there, please have a one-night play with me.
望む シミの数が 鈍く
The number of desired stains... dully...
心に 刺さる
Piercing the heart.
濡れて 尾を引いた花
The flower that got wet and trailed along.
望む 果てなき 宵は哀し
Yearning for the endless night, so sad.
此の指を 貴方の首に 吐息溢れ 鳴かせて
Let these fingers upon your neck, with overflowing sighs, make me cry.
哀しいくらいに感じた 振りの 吉原 今日は雨
The Yoshiwara where I pretended to feel even sadly... today, it's raining.
偽りだらけの恋愛をして 私を丸ごと 飲んで
Engagement in love full of lies, swallow me whole.
哀しいくらいに感じた 振りの 吉原 今日は雨
The Yoshiwara where I pretended to feel even sadly... today, it's raining.
貴方様 どうか私を 買っていただけないでしょうか
You there, would you please buy me?
咲き出す 傘の胸に 濡れる
Blooming in the chest of an umbrella, getting wet.
私は、雨
I am the rain.
千本桜
Senbonzakura
大胆不敵にハイカラ革命
Fearless and daring, a high-collar revolution
磊々落々反戦国家
Open and honest, an anti-war nation
日の丸印の二輪車転がし
Rolling a bicycle with the Hinomaru mark
悪霊退散 ICBM
Exorcising evil spirits, ICBM
環状線を走り抜けて
Running through the loop line
東奔西走なんのその
Running east and west, thinking nothing of it
少年少女戦国無双
Boys and girls, peerless in the warring states
浮世のまにまに
Going with the flow of the floating world
千本桜 夜に紛れ 君の声も届かないよ
Thousand cherry blossoms, fading into the night,
even your voice can't reach
此処は宴 鋼の檻 その断頭台で見下ろして
Here is a banquet, a steel cage,
look down from that guillotine
三千世界 常世の闇 嘆く唄も聞こえないよ
The entire universe, the darkness of the afterlife,
even the grieving song can't be heard
青藍の空 遥か彼方 その光線銃で打ち抜いて
Indigo sky, far in the distance,
shoot through it with that ray gun
百戦錬磨の見た目は将校
Looking like an officer, a veteran of a hundred battles
いったりきたりの花魁道中
Coming and going, an oiran procession
アイツもコイツも皆で集まれ 聖者の行進 ワン・ツー・三・四
Everyone, come together, the march of the saints,
one, two, three, four
禅定門を潜り抜けて
Passing through the gate of meditation
安楽浄土厄払い
Exorcising evil in the Land of Bliss
きっと最後は大団円
Surely the end will be a grand finale
拍手の合間に
In the interval of applause
千本桜 夜に紛れ 君の声も届かないよ
Thousand cherry blossoms, fading into the night,
even your voice can't reach
此処は宴 鋼の檻 その断頭台で見下ろして
Here is a banquet, a steel cage,
look down from that guillotine
三千世界 常世の闇 嘆く唄も聞こえないよ
The entire universe, the darkness of the afterlife,
even the grieving song can't be heard
希望の丘 遥か彼方 その閃光弾を打ち上げろ
Hill of hope, far in the distance,
launch that flash grenade
環状線を走り抜けて
Running through the loop line
東奔西走なんのその
Running east and west, thinking nothing of it
少年少女戦国無双
Boys and girls, peerless in the warring states
浮世のまにまに
Going with the flow of the floating world
千本桜 夜に紛れ 君の声も届かないよ
Thousand cherry blossoms, fading into the night,
even your voice can't reach
此処は宴 鋼の檻 その断頭台を飛び降りて
Here is a banquet, a steel cage,
jump off that guillotine
千本桜 夜に紛れ 君が歌い 僕は踊る
Thousand cherry blossoms, fading into the night,
you sing and I dance
此処は宴 鋼の檻 さあ光線銃を撃ちまくれ
Here is a banquet, a steel cage,
now, fire that ray gun like crazy
希望の模索 遥か彼方 その戦場から打ちまくれ
Searching for hope, far in the distance,
fire away from that battlefield
はーい！ということで！
Yes! And so!
いやぁ、みんな、どうでしたかにゃ？
So, everyone, how was it, nya?
みて！キャストオフできるんですにゃ！
Look! I can cast off, nya!
うわぁ、ありがとー！可愛いありがとー！
Whoa, thank you! Thank you for saying I'm cute!
あのね、ダンスがね、しやすいように、みこ、いつもこう袖とか、
You see, so that it's easy to dance,
Miko always has these sleeves and stuff,
あったりとかするのに、結構ね、あの、大変だったりとかして、
and it was actually quite, you know, difficult,
ちょっとね、ダンスをしやすい感じで、袖もね、取れるようにしてみました。
so I made it so that it's easy to dance,
and the sleeves can be removed.
していただきました！ありがとー！
I had them made like this! Thank you!
あとね、みて！リボンも取れるんだよ！
Also, look! The ribbon can be removed too!
あ、おケツ！
Oh, my butt!
おケツ、おケツですね！
My butt, it's my butt!
で、みてみて！しっぽ！ふわ、ぶら、ぶら！
And look, look! My tail! Fluffy, swing, swing!
はい、ということで！
All right, and so!
もうちょっとね、み、み、見せたいんですけど、
I want to show you, m-m-more, but...
皆さん、あの、次でね、最後の曲になるんですよ。
everyone, the next one will be the last song.
その前に！
Before that!
みんな分かるよね？告知がありますので！
You all know what's coming, right?
There's an announcement!
いいですか？告知させていただいて。
Is it okay? May I make the announcement?
それでは！じゃあ、告知、どうぞ！
Then! Here is the announcement!
じゃーん！3D新衣装記念2022！
Tada! 3D New Outfit Commemoration 2022!
本日22時から発売です！やったー！かわいい！
On sale starting tonight at 10:00 PM! Yay! So cute!
ということで、じゃあ、詳しく見ていきますか？ほい！
So then, let's take a closer look, shall we? Here we go!
おっ、こちらがね、あの、内容になっております。
Oh, here's the lineup.
えっと、あのセットもあったり単品もあったり...
Um, there's a full set and individual items as well...
あ、来た来た来た来た！こちらですね。バーン！
Ah, here they are! This is it. Bam!
まあ一つずつ紹介していきましょう。
Well, let's introduce them one by one.
あい！
Right!
はい、まずは、こちら！めっちゃ可愛いでしょ？新衣装の。
Okay, first is this! Isn't it super cute? With the new outfit.
新衣装の...あ、っと...あ、っと...まずはこの後のやつだね。
The new outfit... oh... um... first is the one after this.
これ忘れてたみか。あ、はい。
I almost forgot this one. Oh, right.
こちらがね、新衣装のイラストとなっております。
This is an illustration of the new outfit.
黒兎先生が書いてくれました。ありがとうございます。
Kurousagi-sensei illustrated it. Thank you very much.
こちらはですね、卓上の屏風？
This is a tabletop folding screen.
屏風であってる？屏風になっております。
Is "folding screen" right? It's a folding screen.
あの立てられたり、角にね、あの金の何か装飾もあって、とっても豪華です！
Um, you can stand it up, and the corners have gold decorations, it's very luxurious!
続いて！
Next!
わー！湯呑み！
Wow! A tea cup!
こちらもね、あの新衣装の、みこになっております。
This one also features Miko in her new outfit.
新衣装のみこが2パターンいて。
There are two patterns of Miko in her new outfit.
で、みこぴーと金時とたい焼きがあります。
And there's Mikopi, Kintoki, and a taiyaki.
リズ先生に書いていただきました。めっちゃ可愛い！使ってね。
Liz-sensei illustrated it. It's so cute! Please use it.
はい、続いて。ジャーン！
Okay, next. Tada!
みんな覚えている？
Everyone, do you remember?
あの、みおちゃんとすばるちゃんと一緒に行ったね。
I went with Mio-chan and Subaru-chan.
温泉旅行で書いた「あきらめんや心に」の絵皿なんですけど。
The "Don't give up in your heart" pictorial plate that I painted during our hot spring trip.
今回、見て、作らせていただきました！イエイ！
This time, look, I had it made! Yay!
みんな欲しいって言ってたから作ってみたけど、買ってくれるかな？
Everyone said they wanted it, so I tried making it. I wonder if you'll buy it?
買ってね。
Please buy it.
こちらはですね、あのリズ先生のイラストもあったり、みこが書きました。
This one has Liz-sensei's illustration and Miko's handwriting.
で、お皿飾れるスタンド付きになっております。
And it comes with a stand to display the plate.
飾っても使えます。よろしくお願いします。続いて！
You can use it as decor. Thank you! Next!
はい、こちらはみこのね、新衣装のアクリルスタンドとなっております。
Yes, this is an acrylic stand of Miko in her new outfit.
ちょっと大きめかな？ちょっとだけ大きめ。
Is it a bit large? Just a little bit large.
で、みこの衣装のモチーフの台座が付いてます。やったー！
And it comes with a base featuring Miko's outfit motif. Yay!
続いて！はい、フルセット購入特典には...
Next! Yes, for the full set purchase bonus...
みこからのメッセージが書いてある、えー複製サイン、箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカードがついてます！イエイ！
A postcard with a message from Miko, um... a signature... a foil-stamped replica signature and message! Yay!
わー、可愛いね。
Wow, it's cute.
ま、ここのねメッセージはね、何を書いているかはお楽しみ。
Well, look forward to seeing what the message says.
結構書いた。結構落書きした。
I wrote a lot. I doodled quite a bit.
はい、ということでお楽しみに。ぜひ買ってください。買ってね。
Yes, so please look forward to it. Please buy it. Buy it, okay?
はい、ということで。じゃあみんなが気になってたシルエット、もうちょっと出ちゃってきたけど。
All right then. Now, the silhouette everyone was curious about... it's peeked out a bit already.
あの、このあと、最後の曲です！みんな！
Um, after this is the last song! Everyone!
今日は見てくれて本当にありがとう。
Thank you so much for watching today.
あ、このあとメンバ限定もあるのでメンバーも、あのよろしくお願いします。
Oh, there's a members-only stream after this, so please check that out too.
メンバーも入ってね。ありがとう。
Join the membership! Thank you.
3Dでありよう。
Let's do it in 3D.
それでは、最後の曲聴いてください。
Now, please listen to the last song.
アシタノハナタチ。
Ashita no Hanatachi.
アシタノハナタチ
The Flowers of Tomorrow
あなたの強さを知る
I'll know your strength
ひと凪ぎ　幻　名もなきもの
A brief moment, an illusion, a nameless thing
心を叩きましょう
Let's knock on our hearts
淡く咲き花たちよ
O faintly blooming flowers
しなやかに　しなるツルの香
Is it the scent of a gracefully bending vine?
ふところに　隠した棘の影
The shadow of a thorn hidden in the heart
それぞれに　言葉にならぬ
Each with wordless...
昨日抱えて　空に向かってゆく
Holding onto yesterday, heading toward the sky
願いを叫べ　命の限り
Shout out your wishes with all your life
やがて星を貫く
Eventually piercing the stars
長い短い　時間の果てに
At the end of time, long or short
あなたの生きた証はそば
The proof you lived is nearby...
土を押し上げて
Pushing up through the soil
明日芽を出し　やがて大きな
Sprouting tomorrow, eventually becoming a large...
花を咲かせる
Bringing flowers into bloom
アシタノハナタチ
The Flowers of Tomorrow
それは取るに足らない　まるで風の前の綿毛
It's something insignificant, like fluff before the wind
寄りなす隙間に流れ
Flowing through the gaps gathered together,
大地にのみ込まれてゆく
It is swallowed by the earth.
やさしげに香る徒花
A transient flower with a gentle fragrance,
しなやかに佇むその姿
Standing there so gracefully.
紡いだ瞳にほども
In those spun eyes,
甘い秘めて空を担う
Harboring sweetness and bearing the sky.
背を向けて逃げるがいいさ
You might as well turn your back and run;
誰もあなたを責められはしない
No one will be able to blame you.
どうせいつかは消えゆく花を
A flower that will eventually fade away,
それでも空に立ち向かったわ
But still, it faced the sky.
手折られることなく
Without being plucked,
明日になれば
When tomorrow comes,
花になるのか
Will it become a flower?
星になるのか
Will it become a star?
願いを叫べ命の限り
Shout your wish with all your might,
やがて想いは星を貫く
And soon your feelings will pierce the stars.
長い短い時間の果てに
At the end of time, long or short,
あなたの生きた証はさあ
The proof that you lived, well...
土を押し上げて明日芽を出し
Will push up the soil and sprout tomorrow,
やがて大きな花を咲かす
And eventually bloom into a large flower.
背を向けて逃げるがいいさ
You might as well turn your back and run;
誰もあなたを責められはしない
No one will be able to blame you.
どうせいつかは消えゆく花を
A flower that will eventually fade away,
それでも空に立ち向かったわ
But still, it faced the sky.
手折られることなく
Without being plucked,
明日になれば
When tomorrow comes,
やがて綻びな
It will soon begin to bloom,
花を咲かせ
Making the flowers bloom...
アシタハナタチ
Flowers of Tomorrow.
さくらみこ新衣装お披露目LIVE
Sakura Miko New Outfit Reveal LIVE